<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.0.1/eml.xsd" packageId="1f0c6e49-d242-4246-9519-8d96ea74cb07" system="https://symbiota.org" scope="system" xml:lang="eng"><dataset><title xml:lang="eng">CCH2 Portal general data extract</title><creator id="e48fca90-c3c1-46c0-ab72-ff8a7bb13c05"><organizationName>CCH2 Portal</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>jyost@calpoly.edu</electronicMailAddress><onlineUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/index.php</onlineUrl></creator><metadataProvider><organizationName>CCH2 Portal</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>jyost@calpoly.edu</electronicMailAddress><onlineUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/index.php</onlineUrl></metadataProvider><pubDate>2026-03-15</pubDate><language>eng</language><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Harencar</surName><givenName>Julia</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>jgharencar@ucdavis.edu</electronicMailAddress><role>datasetOriginator</role><organizationName>University of California, Davis</organizationName><positionName>Dr.</positionName><address><city>Davis</city><administrativeArea>CA</administrativeArea><postalCode>95616</postalCode><country>United States</country></address></associatedParty></dataset><additionalMetadata><metadata><symbiota id="e48fca90-c3c1-46c0-ab72-ff8a7bb13c05"><dateStamp>2026-03-15T20:05:43-07:00</dateStamp><citation identifier="7b06e93b-8bcf-45fd-ab9f-2f52cfb27a10">CCH2 Portal - 7b06e93b-8bcf-45fd-ab9f-2f52cfb27a10</citation><physical><characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding><dataFormat><externallyDefinedFormat><formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName></externallyDefinedFormat></dataFormat></physical><collection identifier="7f373aaa-770f-4bd4-a001-081561f8e833" id="1"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=1</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>CAS</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>BOT-BC</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>CAS - California Academy of Sciences Vascular Plants</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/cas-bot-bc.gif</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://www.calacademy.org/scientists/botany</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>CAS - California Academy of Sciences Vascular Plants (CAS-CAS)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Magnaghi</surName><givenName>Emily</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>emagnaghi@calacademy.org</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>CAS, DS. Worldwide, nearly 1.9 million specimens (27% from California); more than 95% vascular seed plants; the remainder are ferns and a growing collection of bryophytes. Emphasis is on California, North America, Latin America (especially western and southern Mexico and the Galapagos) and Asia (especially China). Vascular plant families and genera that are particularly well represented include Acanthaceae, Brassicaceae, Carex, Eriogonum, Hydrophyllaceae, Lupinus, Asteraceae (particularly Madinae), Malvaceae, Melastomataceae, Onagraceae, Penstemon, Poaceae, Polemoniaceae and Quercus. The herbarium also contains the largest collection of ornamental plants in California.</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="3818c5b4-b6a4-11e8-b408-001a64db2964" id="3"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=3</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>UCR</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>UCR - University of California, Riverside Herbarium - Vascular Plants</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://swbiodiversity.org/seinet/content/collicon/ucr.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://herbarium.ucr.edu/Herbarium.html</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>UCR - University of California, Riverside Herbarium - Vascular Plants (UCR-UCR)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Sanders</surName><givenName>Andrew</givenName></individualName><positionName>Curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>Andrew.Sanders@ucr.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The Herbarium at the University of California, Riverside (UCR) serves as an important source of information for the Southern California regional community as well as for botanists from around the world. UCR specimens and records are used by academic researchers, biological consulting firms, farmers and other individuals involved with plants as a business, research topic, management concern, or just a personal interest. One hundred percent of UCR specimens are databased and 99% are georeferenced (mappable in geographic information systems). Currently UCR is the 5th largest contributor to the Consortium of California Herbaria to CCH2. We have c. 282,350 specimens worldwide. UCR's oldest specimen was taken September 1859 on the Hayden Expedition, Powder River, Wyoming, but most are much more recent (e.g., &amp;gt;8,033 collected after 2015). The UCR Herbarium documents the abundance and distribution of species, including changes in range over time and the arrival of invasive species, the rediscovery of "extinct" species, and the collapse of native plant populations regionally.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;The UCR Herbarium currently (June 4, 2025) houses over 282,350 vascular plant specimens. Of these, c. 81% are from the United States, of which c. 70% are from California. Mexico is represented by c. 40,181 specimens. The rest of the specimens are miscellaneous collections from other areas of the Western Hemisphere from Alaska to Tierra del Fuego. UCR is a general collection, but with particularly strong holdings of Juniperus, Triticeae (B. L. Johnson &amp;amp; J. G. Waines collection of Triticum and relatives), and Phaseolus. It is one of the strongest herbaria for the flora of Southern California and is also strong on the flora of western Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="3818ca8b-b6a4-11e8-b408-001a64db2964" id="4"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=4</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>PUA</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>PUA - Pacific Union College Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://swbiodiversity.org/seinet/content/collicon/pua.gif</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>PUA - Pacific Union College Herbarium (PUA-PUA)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Wyrick</surName><givenName>Aimee</givenName></individualName><positionName>Director and Curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>herbarium@puc.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specialty:&lt;/strong&gt; Vascular plants of coastal regions from San Francisco Bay to southern Oregon; Napa County, California; Klamath Mountains; Arizona; Nevada. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date Founded:&lt;/strong&gt; 1967&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="3818ccc0-b6a4-11e8-b408-001a64db2964" id="5"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=5</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>HNT</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>HNT - Huntington Botanical Gardens Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://swbiodiversity.org/seinet/content/collicon/hnt.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://huntington.org/herbarium</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>HNT - Huntington Botanical Gardens Herbarium (HNT-HNT)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Thibault</surName><givenName>Tim</givenName></individualName><positionName>Herbarium Contact</positionName><electronicMailAddress>tthibault@huntington.org</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Alexander</surName><givenName>Jason</givenName></individualName><positionName>Data Contact (Interim)</positionName><electronicMailAddress>jason_alexander@berkeley.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>The Huntington Botanical Gardens Herbarium (HNT) was founded in the 1960’s by Myron Kimnach, director of the botanical gardens from 1962 to 1986. It is a depository of mostly exotic plant specimens used in research and teaching. The purpose of these specimens is to serve as voucher documentation for research projects, and as resources for plant identification. With over 10,000 specimens, it is an archive of vascular plants from around the world, with particular emphasis on plants from Mexico, Central America and South America. Important collections include those of F. Boutin, J. P. Folsom, D. R. Hodel, D. de Laubenfels, M. Kimnach and R. Moran. Plant families well-represented include Arecaceae, Cactaceae, Crassulaceae, Euphorbiaceae, and desert plants worldwide. In addition, the herbarium receives and provides loans of plant specimens used in active systematic research.</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="3818d002-b6a4-11e8-b408-001a64db2964" id="6"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=6</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>SDSU</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>SDSU - Vascular Plants of the San Diego State University Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/sdsu.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://herbarium.sdsu.edu</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>SDSU - Vascular Plants of the San Diego State University Herbarium (SDSU-SDSU)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Simpson</surName><givenName>Michael</givenName></individualName><positionName>Curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>sdsuherbarium@sdsu.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Califf</surName><givenName>Andria</givenName></individualName><positionName>Collections Manager</positionName><electronicMailAddress>acaliff@sdsu.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The San Diego State University Herbarium (SDSU) is a depository of over 27,000 pressed and mounted specimens of vascular plants and over 400 specimens of algae, used in research and teaching. We have also initiated a bryophyte and lichen collection. The purpose of these specimens is to serve as: 1) voucher documentation for research projects; 2) resources for plant identification; and 3) exemplars in plant courses. In addition, the herbarium both receives and provides loans of plant specimens used in active systematic research. The herbarium collection specializes in land plant specimens from San Diego County, California, and Baja California, with some collections from Australia, Chile, and the south Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="3818d1b3-b6a4-11e8-b408-001a64db2964" id="7"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=7</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>SCFS</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>SCFS - Sagehen Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://sernecportal.org/portal/content/collicon/scfs.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>SCFS - Sagehen Herbarium (SCFS-SCFS)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Faerthen Felix</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>faerthen@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The Sagehen Herbarium is comprised of two related collections: Flora of the Sagehen Basin (approx. 1600 specimens) and Flora of the North Fork of the American River Headwaters&amp;nbsp;(approx. 200 specimens).&amp;nbsp;Both are designed to be synoptic teaching collections for their respective regions. Sagehen Basin is approximately 9000-acres, encompassing a diverse cross section of the Sierra Nevada from the alpine zone near the Pacific Crest (el. 8500 ft) to the eastern slope approaching the Great Basin (el. 6000 ft). Sagehen's collection began in 1963. Important collectors and determiners include B. Trowbridge, G. H. True, Jr., W. Savage, E. Krimmel and F. Felix.&amp;nbsp; The 20,000-acre North Fork American River headwaters on the west slope of the Sierra Nevada is comprised of Chickering American River Reserve, North Fork Association Lands, Onion Creek Experimental Forest, other US Forest Service land, and a few other small private in-holdings. It includes habitats such as black oak woodlands, montane and subalpine coniferous forests, aspen groves, willow thickets, mixed riparian woodland, wet and dry subalpine meadows, montane chaparral, alpine lake margins, and fell fields. Major collectors are R. Palmer, B. Corbin, S. Chickering, E. Krimmel, and F. Felix. Flora of the North Fork American River collection began in Summer 2013, with the goal of establishing voucher specimens to document this reserve's plant list. Both the Sagehen Creek and North Fork American River collections are actively being added to at a rate of 50-300 per field season, including mounting and accessioning of old specimens from 1963-1981. E. Krimmel updated the collection taxonomy in May, 2011. With the release of TJM2, A. Gallandt (2018) and F. Felix (2020) updated the collection again. Collection imaged by E. Krimmel and F. Felix at Cal Poly's Hoover Herbarium (2019-2021). Georeferenced by F. Felix (2016, 2020). Info: https://bit.ly/2ULvfTs&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="3818d582-b6a4-11e8-b408-001a64db2964" id="9"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=9</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>GMDRC</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>GMDRC - Sweeney Granite Mountains Desert Research Center</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://swbiodiversity.org/seinet/content/collicon/gmdrc.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>GMDRC - Sweeney Granite Mountains Desert Research Center (GMDRC-GMDRC)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>André</surName><givenName>Jim</givenName></individualName><positionName>Contact</positionName><electronicMailAddress>gmdrc@ucr.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>La Doux</surName><givenName>Tasha</givenName></individualName><positionName>Contact</positionName><electronicMailAddress>gmdrc@ucr.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The University of California&amp;rsquo;s Sweeney Granite Mountains Desert Research Center Herbarium (GMDRC) houses nearly 19,000 vascular plant specimens, available to researchers and visiting classes at the GMDRC. This regional herbarium holds specimens from the western U.S. with a primary focus on the transmontane bioregions of California, Nevada, Arizona and Utah. The collection is fully databased (Filemaker Pro) and photo-digitized.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="3818d95b-b6a4-11e8-b408-001a64db2964" id="12"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=12</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>OBI</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>OBI - Robert F. Hoover Herbarium, Cal Poly State University</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/obi.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://bio.calpoly.edu</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>OBI - Robert F. Hoover Herbarium, Cal Poly State University (OBI-OBI)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Yost</surName><givenName>Jenn</givenName></individualName><positionName>Director and Associate Professor</positionName><electronicMailAddress>jyost@calpoly.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Pearson</surName><givenName>Katie</givenName></individualName><positionName>Assistant curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>kdpearso@calpoly.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The Hoover Herbarium houses 95,000+ specimens of vascular plants, algae, lichens, and bryophytes. The geographic focus is San Luis Obispo County, California. The collection also includes many specimens from other areas of California, other states of the US, particularly Arizona, and some from other regions of the world, especially Mexico. Emphasis areas in the collection include Asteraceae, Lupinus, and cultivated Eucalyptus. Major collections include Robert F. Hoover (1946&amp;ndash;1969), David J. Keil (1966&amp;ndash;present), Rhonda Riggins (1970s&amp;ndash;2000), Tracy Call (mostly Apiaceae&amp;mdash;late 1940s&amp;ndash;1960s), and Robert J. Rodin (1940s&amp;ndash;1977). The collection is used extensively in undergraduate teaching and training. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Important Collections: Robert F. Hoover (1946&amp;ndash;1969), David J. Keil (1966&amp;ndash;present), Rhonda Riggins (1970s&amp;ndash;2000), Tracy Call (mostly Apiaceae&amp;mdash;late 1940s&amp;ndash;1960s), and Robert J. Rodin (1940s&amp;ndash;1977)&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="3818da9e-b6a4-11e8-b408-001a64db2964" id="13"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=13</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>UCSC</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>UCSC Herbarium - Kenneth S. Norris Center for Natural History, University of California Santa Cruz</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://nansh.org/portal/content/collicon/ucsc.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://norriscenter.ucsc.edu/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>UCSC Herbarium - Kenneth S. Norris Center for Natural History, University of California Santa Cruz (UCSC-UCSC)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Chris Lay (Administrative Director); Al Keuter (Vascular Plants Curator)</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>cml@ucsc.edu; akeuter@ucsc.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The UCSC Herbarium at the Kenneth S. Norris Center for Natural History (UC Santa Cruz) houses more than 20,000 vascular plants, algae, lichens, bryophytes, and fungi. The collection focuses primarily on mostly native organisms from Santa Cruz County and the University of California Reserves but also contains important specimens from throughout California and occasionally those of interest from elsewhere around the world. The research collection archives research and publication voucher specimens and the student collection serves as a university educational resource. Notable collections within the UCSC Herbarium include those of R. Morgan (vascular plants 1969-2017), Dylan Neubauer (collections of interest from throughout California), David Styer (Fort Ord National Monument), Neal Kramer (Bonny Doon Ecological Reserve), Ken Kellman, Al Keuter (collections from California, Oregon, elsewhere in the US and Bermuda) and Bureau of Land Management collections from Cotoni-Coast Dairies National Monument.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="3818e0aa-b6a4-11e8-b408-001a64db2964" id="16"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=16</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>SBBG</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>SBBG - Clifton Smith Herbarium, Santa Barbara Botanic Garden</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/sbbg.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://www.sbbg.org/explore-garden/pritzlaff-conservation-center/herbarium</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>SBBG - Clifton Smith Herbarium, Santa Barbara Botanic Garden (SBBG-SBBG)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Guilliams</surName><givenName>C. Matt</givenName></individualName><positionName>Curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>mguilliams@sbbotanicgarden.org</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Ayers</surName><givenName>Annie</givenName></individualName><positionName>Collections Manager</positionName><electronicMailAddress>aayers@sbbotanicgarden.org</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The SBBG natural history collections house the region's largest scientific collection of preserved Central Coast and California Channel Islands vascular plants, bryophytes, lichens, and macrofungi. Across these collections, the Garden curates approximately 214,000 specimens. Vascular plant specimen data are served on this portal (https://cch2.org/). Lichen specimen data are served on the Consortium of North American Lichen Herbaria (https://lichenportal.org/cnalh/). Macrofungus specimen data are served on the Mycology Collections Portal (https://mycoportal.org/portal/index.php). Bryophyte data are served on the Consortium of Bryophyte Herbaria (https://bryophyteportal.org/portal/).&lt;code style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: inherit; padding: 0px; font-family: Menlo, Monaco, Consolas, 'Courier New', monospace; color: inherit; background-color: transparent; border-radius: 0px; white-space: pre-wrap;"&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="3818e1d3-b6a4-11e8-b408-001a64db2964" id="17"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=17</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>RSA</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>VascularPlants</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>RSA - California Botanic Garden Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/rsa-vascularplants.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://www.calbg.org/collections/herbarium</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>RSA - California Botanic Garden Herbarium (RSA-RSA)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Mare Nazaire, Administrative Curator</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>mnazaire@calbg.org</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The combined Herbarium of California Botanic Garden (RSA) and Pomona College (POM) is a museum-quality collection of vascular plant and bryophyte specimens. With current holdings totaling over 1,250,000 specimens, the Herbarium is the third largest in California. The Herbarium is recognized throughout the world for its strength in documenting the diversity, distribution, variation, and ecology of more than 6,500 species of flowering plants, conifers, and ferns in California, which constitutes nearly 50% of the total collection. The holdings from Southern California exceed 250,000 and are unsurpassed by any other herbarium. Approximately 95% of the collection is composed of mounted sheets and filed according to a standardized system of classification. Ancillary collections that augment the collection include a cone &amp;amp; fruit collection, wood collection, fluid preserved collection, and pollen and anatomy slide collection.&lt;code style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: inherit; padding: 0px; font-family: Menlo, Monaco, Consolas, 'Courier New', monospace; color: inherit; background-color: transparent; border-radius: 0px; white-space: pre-wrap;"&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="3818e5a2-b6a4-11e8-b408-001a64db2964" id="19"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=19</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>LOB</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>LOB - California State University, Long Beach Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://swbiodiversity.org/seinet/content/collicon/lob.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://web.csulb.edu/colleges/cnsm/collections/plants/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>LOB - California State University, Long Beach Herbarium (LOB-LOB)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Amanda Fisher</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>Amanda.Fisher@csulb.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The herbarium has approximately 18,000 specimens preserved as dried, pressed specimens.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="a70436a2-dfaa-482e-88e0-5193a66b0bfc" id="34"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=34</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>LA</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>LA - University of California, Los Angeles Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/la.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://sites.lifesci.ucla.edu/eeb-herbarium</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>LA - University of California, Los Angeles Herbarium (LA-LA)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Baniaga</surName><givenName>Anthony</givenName></individualName><positionName>Curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>abaniaga@ucla.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The UCLA Herbarium (LA) was founded in ca. 1930, and contains approximately 150,000 specimens, almost entirely dried vascular plants. The herbarium contains collections of notable UCLA biologists such as A. M. Johnson, Carl C. Epling, Margaret and Harlan Lewis, Peter H. Raven, Martin L. Cody, Henry J. Thompson, Jonathan Sauer, Joseph Andorfer Ewan, Elizabeth McClintock, Mildred E. Mathias, Lawrence L. Kiefer, Barbara Joe Hoshizaki and Barry A. Prigge. The core of the collection contains specimens collected between 1920-1970 from North America (75%), South America (13%), Asia &amp;amp; the Pacific (10%), Europe (1%), and Africa (1%). The UCLA Herbarium also maintains a Santa Monica Mountains Collection and Los Angeles Basin (ca. 12,000 specimens), a Baja California Collection (ca. 4,000 specimens), a Type Collection (500 specimens), and a &lt;span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Open Sans', 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;"&gt;collection of cultivated plants from 1900-1960 West Los Angeles (ca. 8,000 specimens)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Open Sans', 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;"&gt;. Additional collection strengths include the Crassulaceae, Lamiaceae, Loasaceae, and Onagraceae clades.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="f7e112f9-92c5-455c-a6c4-709b0f8d7f73" id="35"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=35</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>UCSB</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>UCSB - University of California Santa Barbara Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/ucsb.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://ccber.ucsb.edu</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>UCSB - University of California Santa Barbara Herbarium (UCSB-UCSB)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Greg Wahlert</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>wahlert@ccber.ucsb.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>The University of California, Santa Barbara (UCSB) Herbarium has approximately 120,000 herbarium specimens of vascular plants, lichens, bryophytes, and marine macroalgae. The herbarium is housed at the Cheadle Center for Biodiversity and Ecological Restoration on the campus of UCSB. The vascular plant collection consist mainly of specimens from Santa Barbara County, including the northern Channel Islands, with additional collections from San Luis Obispo, Kern, and Ventura Counties, the southern Sierra Nevada region, southern California, and northern Mexico. Special collections include the J. R. Haller pine collection (5,000 specimens), with emphasis on population-level sampling of many western North American pine species, and the Cornelius H. Muller oak collection, with ca. 7,000 specimens from the USA and Mexico. Also conserved in the herbarium are ca. 69,000 slide preparations and spirit collections of Vernon I. Cheadle and Katherine Esau. There are 43 type specimens of plants and marine macroalgae. Incorporated collections include the Santa Rosa Island Reserve (SCIR) herbarium (1,500) and the marine macroalgae of the Santa Barbara Museum of Natural History (1,035), which contains some of the earliest collections of California seaweeds. Greg Wahlert is the current collections manager. Taxonomy and nomenclature follow the second edition of the Jepson Manual (Baldwin et al., 2012). Financial assistance with digitization efforts is provided in part by the UCSB Coastal Fund.</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="7591c177-2bde-4641-9b60-32f68cbbd1f4" id="36"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=36</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>MACF</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>MACF - MacFadden Herbarium, California State University Fullerton</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/macf.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://www.fullerton.edu/biology/facilities/herbarium/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>MACF - MacFadden Herbarium, California State University Fullerton (MACF-MACF)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Joshua Der</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>jder@fullerton.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;MacFadden Herbarium is operated by the Department of Biological Science at Cal State Fullerton and houses over 30, 000 vascular plant specimens. The herbarium is named for botanist Fay A. MacFadden, who sold her extensive collection of plants to the university just prior to her death in 1964. The collection is used as research and teaching tools by our faculty, staff, students, and other researchers.&lt;code style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: inherit; padding: 0px; font-family: Menlo, Monaco, Consolas, 'Courier New', monospace; color: inherit; background-color: transparent; border-radius: 0px; white-space: pre-wrap;"&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="fbf9653f-f51b-4e99-9820-d65161437a24" id="37"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=37</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>IRVC</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>IRVC - University of California, Irvine Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/irvc.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://arboretum.bio.uci.edu/plant-exhibits/h</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>IRVC - University of California, Irvine Herbarium (IRVC-IRVC)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Rebecca Crowe</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>rcrowe@uci.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Bowler</surName><givenName>Peter</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>pabowler@uci.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;Western U.S., especially southern California and Orange County; Baja California, Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="8126927b-7459-411e-acc7-7aa06631920b" id="38"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=38</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>FSC</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>FSC - Fresno State Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/fsc.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://waselkovlab.com/herbarium/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>FSC - Fresno State Herbarium (FSC-FSC)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Dr. Katherine Waselkov</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>kwaselkov@csufresno.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The geographical specialty of the FSC is Fresno County and parts of surrounding Inyo, Kern, Madera, Mono, and Tulare Counties: including the Sierra Nevada mountains, the San Joaquin Valley, and the Mojave Desert. About nine-tenths of the accessioned collection, or 31,500 specimens, is from California, with the remaining tenth from other states and countries. We estimate that half of the California collections are from high Sierra Nevada ecosystems (above 7000 feet), as this was Quibell&amp;rsquo;s focal collecting area. The other half of the collection represents the San Joaquin Valley itself, including riverine ecosystems, vernal pools, and agricultural ecosystems; the western Diablo Range region between Panoche and Coalinga; and the eastern slope of the Sierra Nevada, including the northern extent of the Mojave Desert. There is no particular taxonomic speciality among vascular plants, and only about ~100 of the specimens are federally or state listed as rare, threatened, or endangered (representing 29 taxa). Collectors who frequently contributed to the FSC collection: Charles H. Quibell (founder of the herbarium in 1925 and Fresno State biology professor); John "Jack" Springer, a USFS employee whose private herbarium of 1930s California grass collections was donated to FSC; Rimo C. Bacigalupi, first curator of the Jepson Herbarium, with collections from the 1950s and 1960s; Philip A. Munz from Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden and Pomona College, who collected in the 1920s-1950s and provided many of the FSC specimen determinations for specimens collected by Charles H. Quibell; John &amp;ldquo;Jack&amp;rdquo; Rockwell, who collected in the Fresno area in the mid-20th century and whose specimens are almost entirely confined to FSC; and John H. Weiler, FSC Herbarium curator and Scrophulariaceae specialist.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="cc54a5fd-2e20-4ea6-8871-b2af436d9de3" id="39"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=39</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>DAV</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>Vascular Plants</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>DAV - University of California, Davis Center for Plant Diversity - Vascular Plants</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/dav.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://herbarium.ucdavis.edu</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>DAV - University of California, Davis Center for Plant Diversity - Vascular Plants (DAV-DAV)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Barry</surName><givenName>Teri</givenName></individualName><positionName>Collections Manager</positionName><electronicMailAddress>tcbarry@ucdavis.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Colwell</surName><givenName>Alison</givenName></individualName><positionName>Curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>aelcolwell@ucdavis.edu</electronicMailAddress><userId>https://orcid.org/0000-0002-3011-3933</userId></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;University of California, Davis herbarium vascular plant collections are worldwide, with emphasis on California, North America, and neotropics (especially Ecuador and Baja California).&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;Our collections are especially strong in the following taxa: Quercus, Fagaceae, and Arctostaphylos, Ericaceae of New World; Euphorbiaceae worldwide; Poaceae of North America; Streptanthaus (Brassicaceae); Clarkia (Onagraceae); Lycianthes and Lycopersicon (Solanaceae); Stephanomeria and tarweed genera (Asteraceae); Navarretia (Polemoniaceae); Allium (Alliaceae); Trifolium (Fabaceae);Prunus (Rosaceae).&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;Our regional strengths are: Central Valley of California vernal pool species; weedy and poisonous species of California and Mediterranean-climate regions; range plants of California; alpine flora of western North America.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;Estimated size of collection: 320,000 specimens, 50% from California. 95% of the California specimens have label data online, 60% also have images online. Specimens outside of California acquired in the past 7 years have label data online and most are also imaged. 4.4% of older non-California specimens are databased. Specimens not online are imaged and databased on request.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="5805f8f3-2733-4c87-bca8-0fd1644490c2" id="40"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=40</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>SFSU</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>SFSU - Vascular Plants of the Harry D. Thiers Herbarium at San Francisco State University</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://www.cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/sfsu.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://cantleylab.wixsite.com/jasoncantley/sfsu-herbarium</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>SFSU - Vascular Plants of the Harry D. Thiers Herbarium at San Francisco State University (SFSU-SFSU)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Jason T. Cantley</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>cantley@sfsu.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The Harry D. Thiers Herbarium at San Francisco State University maintains over 220,000 specimens. Its primary research focus is mycological, but there are roughly 27,000 vascular plant specimens. Special vascular plant collections of SFSU include the California Floristic Province including a particularly large and taxonomically robust collection of Arctostaphylos (Ericaceae).&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="f62b4819-3195-4053-a2dc-07431438f3e6" id="41"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=41</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>SFV</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>SFV - California State University, Northridge</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/sfv.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>SFV - California State University, Northridge (SFV-SFV)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Hogue</surName><givenName>James N.</givenName></individualName><positionName>Collections Manager</positionName><electronicMailAddress>james.n.hogue@csun.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;Primarily vascular plants of California but with holdings in other parts of North America and some other places worldwide. Vascular plant specimens are on herbarium sheets, bryophytes and lichens are in paper packets. We have nearly 25,000 specimens.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="9a7f2f77-3288-4d40-8baa-2f55b8450b7f" id="42"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=42</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>CSLA</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>CSLA - Cal State LA Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/csla.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>CSLA - Cal State LA Herbarium (CSLA-CSLA)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Fisher</surName><givenName>Kirsten</givenName></individualName><positionName>Curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>kfisher2@exchange.calstatela.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The CSLA Herbarium holds approximately 35,000 dry-mounted vascular plant specimens from around the world, with particular collection emphasis in Southern California and Northern Mexico. Founded in 1956, CSLA contains significant collections from J. Henrickson, B. Prigge, and R. M. Straw.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="0945030a-f625-4b95-9f48-e5cb7d6eb879" id="43"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=43</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>SD</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>SD - SD Herbarium, San Diego Natural History Museum</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/sd.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://www.sdnhm.org/science/botany/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>SD - SD Herbarium, San Diego Natural History Museum (SD-SD)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Layla Aerne Hains</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>laerne@sdnhm.org</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The San Diego Natural History Museum Department of Botany focuses on biodiversity, evolutionary history research, and documentation of the flora in Southern California, Baja California, and adjacent areas. With a collection dating back to the 1870s, the SD Herbarium is invaluable as a scientific resource that documents regional plant populations and has been used for basic natural history research. Botanists with regional colleges, universities, and museums utilize the collections for their own research and for student projects, both by visiting the collection in person and/or through loans. The SD Herbarium houses over 270,000 accessioned specimens, all of which have been databased. Specimens from southern California account for nearly half of our collection and about 20% of our collection is from Baja California. Nearly all San Diego County and Baja California records have been georeferenced (99%). The Botany Department maintains two web sites that serve researchers with searching and mapping pages, checklists, voucher images, data input forms for collectors, and other tools for using our collections. SDPlantAtlas.org serves researchers interested in the plants of California&amp;rsquo;s San Diego and Imperial Counties. BajaFlora.org serves the needs of researchers interested in the plants of the two states of Baja, Mexico, consolidating the SD collections and the collections of the two primary herbaria in Baja.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="6a942843-3cb1-4643-a475-24df2d2ba49f" id="44"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=44</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>CHSC</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>VascularPlants</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>CHSC - Ahart Herbarium, CSU Chico - Vascular Plants</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://www.cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/chscvascularplants.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://www.csuchico.edu/herbarium/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>CHSC - Ahart Herbarium, CSU Chico - Vascular Plants (CHSC-CHSC)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Janeway</surName><givenName>Lawrence</givenName></individualName><positionName>herbarium curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>ljaneway@csuchico.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Edwards</surName><givenName>Adrienne</givenName></individualName><positionName>herbarium director</positionName><electronicMailAddress>aledwards@csuchico.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The Chico State Herbarium is the most complete repository of plant specimens from northeastern California. The emphasis is on the northern California flora, and includes a great number of rare, threatened, and endangered plant species. Established with specimens donated by the late Professor Vesta Holt in the 1950's, the Herbarium now contains more than 125,000 dried and mounted specimens. The majority of samples are flowering plants, conifers, and ferns, but bryophytes, lichens, and especially slime molds, are also well represented. The Herbarium is used extensively for identification of sensitive and other plant species by various agencies and individuals. Loans of herbarium specimens are made to any higher academic institutions who request them.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="eaef47cb-6ed3-4439-b974-f05e4f65165e" id="45"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=45</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>HSC</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>HSC - Humboldt State University Vascular Plant Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/hsc.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://www2.humboldt.edu/herbarium/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>HSC - Humboldt State University Vascular Plant Herbarium (HSC-HSC)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Robin Bencie</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>mrb1@humboldt.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The Humboldt State University Vascular Plant Herbarium (HSC) consists of ~104,000 specimens, with a strong emphasis in the flora of northwest California and southwest Oregon. Established in 1960, the Herbarium serves as a botanical resource for students and faculty, as well as, community members and professional botanists. Our collections offer excellent opportunities to learn more about the rich diversity of our native flora, as well as, our exotic and invasive weeds. The Herbarium also participates in loan and exchange programs with other herbaria throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="1289d058-5d40-4d9f-b3d3-905276504bbe" id="46"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=46</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>UCJEPS</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>VASC</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>UCJEPS - University and Jepson Herbaria, University of California, Berkeley</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/ucjeps.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://ucjeps.berkeley.edu/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>UCJEPS - University and Jepson Herbaria, University of California, Berkeley (UCJEPS-UCJEPS)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Alexander</surName><givenName>Jason</givenName></individualName><positionName>Data Manager</positionName><electronicMailAddress>jason_alexander@berkeley.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;Established in 1895 around a core of preserved plant specimens that were collected by William Brewer on the California Geological Survey of 1860 to 1864, the University Herbarium (UC) includes 2,200,000 specimens from land plants, algae, lichens, and fungi. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Established in 1950 by a bequest from Willis Linn Jepson, the Jepson Herbarium (JEPS) includes over 100,000 vascular plant specimens from California.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;UC/JEPS publishes a Darwin Core dataset through the Berkeley Natural History Museums IPT and exports that data to GBIF.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style="width: 140px; height: 24px;" src="https://www.gbif.org/api/widgets/literature/button?gbifDatasetKey=83a49751-4282-481e-a847-1c5c224a0551" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="eb19159e-023a-405e-9970-cb1a1c0c1ce5" id="47"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=47</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>CSUSB</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>CSUSB - California State University San Bernardino</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/csusb.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://www.csusb.edu/biology/herbarium</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>CSUSB - California State University San Bernardino (CSUSB-CSUSB)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Lopez Perez</surName><givenName>Lua</givenName></individualName><positionName>Curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>Lua.LopezPerez@csusb.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The herbarium at CSUSB was founded in 1969, four years after the campus opened. The specimens it houses have been collected primarily from San Bernardino and Riverside Counties. The herbarium, however, contains specimens from other counties, states, and countries.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="f253ccf3-5a1c-4b4b-8e49-298212e5c3a4" id="48"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=48</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>BSCA</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>BSCA - Colorado Desert District, California Department of Parks and Recreation</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/bsca.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>BSCA - Colorado Desert District, California Department of Parks and Recreation (BSCA-BSCA)</additionalInfo><abstract></abstract><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Larry Hendrickson</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>Larry.Hendrickson@parks.ca.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty></collection><collection identifier="1ecbac2e-f2c6-4e7b-8561-ed1cc0d30517" id="49"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=49</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>PASA</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>PASA - Pasadena City College Herbarium</collectionName><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>PASA - Pasadena City College Herbarium (PASA-PASA)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Jason Alexander</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>jason_alexander@berkeley.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>The Pasadena City College Herbarium, is a small collection (ca. 2,400 sheets) of vascular plants from S. California. Many of the specimens were collected during the 1920's and 1930's. Notable collectors include early collections from Annetta Carter. The collection was formally given to HNT in 2008.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;b&gt;Herbarium contact:&lt;/b&gt; Sean Lahmeyer (&lt;a href="mailto:slahmeyer@huntington.org"&gt;slahmeyer@huntington.org&lt;/a&gt;)</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="f3fbf434-c09e-46fa-bc30-99138cd73a71" id="50"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=50</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>CDA</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>CDA - California Department of Food and Agriculture</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/cda.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://cdfa.ca.gov/plant/ppd/herbarium.html</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>CDA - California Department of Food and Agriculture (CDA-CDA)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Blomquist</surName><givenName>Cheryl</givenName></individualName><positionName>Environmental Program Manager I</positionName><electronicMailAddress>cheryl.blomquist@cdfa.ca.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Kodira</surName><givenName>Umesh</givenName></individualName><positionName>Environmental Program Manager II</positionName><electronicMailAddress>umesh.kodira@cdfa.ca.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Skibicki</surName><givenName>Samuel</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>samuel.skibicki@cdfa.ca.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;Founded by 1911 as the herbarium of the California Horticultural Commission, the Botany Lab and Herbarium of the California Department of Food and Agriculture (Plant Pest Diagnostics Center) serves as the plant diagnostic and identification service for California, and is the repository for the state collection of noxious weed and agricultural plant specimens. Size of collection: ca. 60,000 plant specimens. Notable collections include those of CDFA and County Agricultural Commissioner staff, M. K. Bellue, T. C. Fuller, G. Douglas Barbe, G. F. Hrusa, D. G Kelch, and G. L. Stout. The Gilbert L. Stout Plant Disease Herbarium (CDA-BPS) has ca. 10,000 unaccessioned specimens, integration into CDA is in progress.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;Collections are available via the CCH2 Portal&lt;br /&gt;Algae collections dataset for the California Department of Food and Agriculture - Algae (CDA) are available via the Macroalgae Portal &lt;br /&gt;Fungi collections dataset for the California Department of Food and Agriculture - Fungi (CDA) are available via the MyCoPortal&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;The CDFA PPDC Seed Herbarium has ca. 30,000 accessions in the Seed and Fruit Collection (CDA SFC), and is curated and databased separately from CDA (curator Emi Kuroiwa). Notable collections in CDA-SFC include those of CDFA and County Agricultural Commissioner staff, M. K. Bellue, B. Crampton, P. B. Kennedy, D. Baxter, B. M. Browning, D. Decker-Walters, and C. Dremann. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;menu id="fcltHTML5Menu1" type="context"&gt;&lt;/menu&gt;&lt;menu id="fcltHTML5Menu1" type="context"&gt;&lt;/menu&gt;&lt;menu id="fcltHTML5Menu1" type="context"&gt;&lt;/menu&gt;&lt;menu id="fcltHTML5Menu1" type="context"&gt;&lt;/menu&gt;&lt;menu id="fcltHTML5Menu1" type="context"&gt;&lt;/menu&gt;&lt;menu id="fcltHTML5Menu1" type="context"&gt;&lt;/menu&gt;&lt;menu id="fcltHTML5Menu1" type="context"&gt;&lt;/menu&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="a4842aeb-dabb-4d59-b809-beaa32966632" id="51"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=51</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>SACT</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>SACT - California State University, Sacramento</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/sact.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>SACT - California State University, Sacramento (SACT-SACT)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>LaForgia</surName><givenName>Marina</givenName></individualName><positionName>Assistant Professor and Director</positionName><electronicMailAddress>marina.laforgia@csus.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The CSU Sacramento herbarium contains vascular plants mostly from California with an emphasis on Placer County flora. Size of collection: ~20,000 specimens.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;Director &amp;amp; Curator (2024-present): Dr. Marina LaForgia&lt;br /&gt;Data Manager 2011-2013 (former): Travis Lawrence.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;Sequoia Hall Rooms 114 &amp;amp; 116&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;Sacramento State University&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;Sacramento, CA 95819&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mailing Addresses&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="s1" style="text-decoration-line: underline;"&gt;USPS:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;CSU Sacramento, Biology&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;6000 J Street, MS 6077&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;Sacramento, CA 95819&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;Attn: Dr. Marina LaForgia&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="s1" style="text-decoration-line: underline;"&gt;UPS/FedEx:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;CSU Sacramento, Biology&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;6000 J Street, TSC 5033&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;Sacramento, CA 95819&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;Attn: Doug Whited/Marina LaForgia&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="25d4de3b-3bf3-40ec-aed6-ca26cf996f7b" id="52"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=52</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>CATA</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>Vascular</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>CATA - Catalina Island Conservancy Herbarium Vascular Plants</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/cata-vascular.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://www.catalinaconservancy.org/index.php?s=about&amp;p=about_cic</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>CATA - Catalina Island Conservancy Herbarium Vascular Plants (CATA-CATA)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Murdoff</surName><givenName>Ryan</givenName></individualName><positionName>Curator, Plant Conservation Manager</positionName><electronicMailAddress>rmurdoff@catalinaconservancy.org</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Dennhardt</surName><givenName>Lauren</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>LDennhardt@catalinaconservancy.org</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Alison</surName><givenName>Kevin</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>KAlison@catalinaconservancy.org</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The Catalina Island Conservancy Herbarium houses about 2,000 vascular plant specimens. All specimens were collected on Santa Catalina Island. 73% of the specimens were collected in the 1970's and 1990's by Mark L. Hoefs.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="c8415d43-4bcc-4a97-81ab-f9879d99cab3" id="53"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=53</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>JROH</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>JROH - Jasper Ridge Biological Preserve, Stanford University</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://www.cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/jroh.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://jrbp.stanford.edu/research/herbarium</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>JROH - Jasper Ridge Biological Preserve, Stanford University (JROH-JROH)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Rawlings</surName><givenName>John</givenName></individualName><positionName>Herbarium &amp; Data Contact</positionName><electronicMailAddress>rawlings@stanford.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Hernandez</surName><givenName>Adriana</givenName></individualName><positionName>Assoc. Dir. of Research</positionName><electronicMailAddress>aher@stanford.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Lambrecht</surName><givenName>Ann</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>alambrec@stanford.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Renshaw</surName><givenName>Diane</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>dlr@ecosystem.com</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>The Oakmead Herbarium at Jasper Ridge Biological Preserve was founded in 1996. All specimens were collected from the 1198 acres (485 ha) now comprising the Jasper Ridge Biological Preserve of Stanford University, San Mateo County, California. Major collectors include John Hunter Thomas (1955-1992), John Rawlings (2004-n) and Toni Corelli (1990-2016). Size of collection: ~5500 specimens.</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="0625702b-27ed-4b22-a65a-f840610bb287" id="56"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=56</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>PGM</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>PGM - Pacific Grove Museum of Natural History</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/pgm.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>PGM - Pacific Grove Museum of Natural History (PGM-PGM)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>King</surName><givenName>Nate</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>king@pgmuseum.org</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The herbarium of the Pacific Grove Museum of Natural History contains approximately 7,500 specimens which are concerned principally with the vascular plants of Monterey County, California and the adjacent inner coast range mountains which border it, including collections from San Benito, western Fresno, and portions of Kings County. Ninety percent of the collections are from Monterey County, California. The herbarium includes the Monterey County collections of Beatrice F. Howitt, duplicates of specimens sent to CAS and identified by J.T. Howell resulting in: &lt;em&gt;The Vascular Plants of Monterey County, California&lt;/em&gt; by Beatrice F. Howeitt and John Thomas Howell, The Wasmann Journal of Biology, Vol. 22, No. 1, Spring 1964 and &lt;em&gt;Supplement&lt;/em&gt; published by The Pacific Grove Museum of Natural History Assoc, July, 1973. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Herbarium contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Paul Vandecarr (&lt;a href="mailto:Vandecarr@pgmuseum.org"&gt;Vandecarr@pgmuseum.org&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="e506cd1d-caf1-4a14-ba5b-c1e247ba9b98" id="59"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=59</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>HREC</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>HREC - Hopland Research and Extension Center</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/hrec.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://hrec.ucanr.edu/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>HREC - Hopland Research and Extension Center (HREC-HREC)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Manager</surName><givenName>Collections</givenName></individualName><positionName>Herbarium Contact</positionName><electronicMailAddress>ucjeps-collections@berkeley.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Alexander</surName><givenName>Jason</givenName></individualName><positionName>Data Contact</positionName><electronicMailAddress>jason_alexander@berkeley.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;UC field station herbarium databased, imaged, and managed by UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="de1c2baf-ff4c-4956-838b-9038ded47e2c" id="60"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=60</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>YM</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>YM - Yosemite National Park</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/ym-yose.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://www.nps.gov/yose/historyculture/collections.htm</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>YM - Yosemite National Park (YM-YM)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Bender</surName><givenName>Laura</givenName></individualName><positionName>Curator of Collections</positionName><electronicMailAddress>laura_bender@nps.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Perrigo</surName><givenName>Kelsey</givenName></individualName><positionName>Registrar</positionName><electronicMailAddress>kelsey_perrigo@nps.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;Yosemite National Park Herbarium is a significant regional collection, with 8,000 specimens, dating from the early part of the 20th century to the present with the bulk of specimens dating from the 1920s to the 1960s. This is an actively growing herbarium, with over 3,000 vascular plant specimens added in the last ten years. The herbarium is a valuable component of the park's museum collections and is an essential tool for resource management: fire management, exotics programs, and vegetation management. It is also a valuable source of information to the scientific community about Yosemite's complex flora. Access to the collections is granted to researchers by advance appointment.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="ccb5582c-5b24-402f-a975-1f9f27e16949" id="61"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=61</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>CLARK</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>CLARK - Riverside Metropolitan Museum, Clark Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/clark.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://www.riversideca.gov/museum/na-plantcom.asp</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>CLARK - Riverside Metropolitan Museum, Clark Herbarium (CLARK-CLARK)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Grimm</surName><givenName>Katie</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>KGrim@riversideca.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Wright</surName><givenName>Ian</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>IWright@riversideca.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The Clark Herbarium (founded in 1949) serves as a reference library to the plant diversity and changes of Southern California. With almost 10,000 specimens, the Clark Herbarium includes dry botanical mounts, most of which were collected from the Riverside region and surrounding counties by J. C. Roos and other botanists between 1920 and 1990. A small collection of lichens and fungi was assembled during the 1930s by Edmund C. Jaeger, and was later donated to the Museum during his tenure as Curator of Plants. All these materials now represent an important database describing the distribution of native plant species in the southwestern U.S., which is now a vastly altered environmental setting. James Bryant, former curator, retired.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="7d1c54a8-bd69-4aaa-bf3d-785f0fd4af43" id="69"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=69</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>SHTC</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>SHTC - CSU Stanislaus Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/shtc.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>SHTC - CSU Stanislaus Herbarium (SHTC-SHTC)</additionalInfo><abstract></abstract><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Gardner</surName><givenName>Andy</givenName></individualName><positionName>Curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>agardner1@csustan.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty></collection><collection identifier="f1a594d4-384d-4b3d-a405-a14bed57ffcc" id="71"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=71</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>MCCC</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>MCCC - Mendocino College Coast Center Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/mccc.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>MCCC - Mendocino College Coast Center Herbarium (MCCC-MCCC)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Teresa Sholars</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>tsholars@mendocino.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;Vascular plants, fungi (lichens and mushrooms), marine algae, mosses, rare plants, vouchers for local consultants and vouchers for Mendocino Flora by Smith and Wheeler.&lt;code style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: inherit; padding: 0px; font-family: Menlo, Monaco, Consolas, 'Courier New', monospace; color: inherit; background-color: transparent; border-radius: 0px; white-space: pre-wrap;"&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="da751016-8e3d-4ba8-9060-439bb741a8a7" id="75"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=75</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>THRI</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>THRI - Herbarium of Sequoia and Kings Canyon National Parks</collectionName><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>THRI - Herbarium of Sequoia and Kings Canyon National Parks (THRI-THRI)</additionalInfo><abstract></abstract><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Huber</surName><givenName>Ann</givenName></individualName><positionName>Plant Ecologist</positionName><electronicMailAddress>ann_huber@nps.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Bonnifield</surName><givenName>Juanita</givenName></individualName><positionName>Cultural Resource Program Manager</positionName></associatedParty></collection><collection identifier="ed6725c2-5a87-4f66-a6ee-e85c3b9ce32d" id="76"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=76</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>PPWD</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>PPWD - Stephen J. Barnhart Herbarium at Pepperwood Preserve</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/ppwd.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>PPWD - Stephen J. Barnhart Herbarium at Pepperwood Preserve (PPWD-PPWD)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Michelle Halbur</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>mhalbur@pepperwoodpreserve.org</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The Stephen J. Barnhart Herbarium at Pepperwood houses specimens of fungi, lichen, and non-vascular and vascular plants collected at Pepperwood Preserve, Sonoma County, California. It includes plants collected by Greg deNevers who worked as the resident biologist for the California Academy of Sciences during the 1980s. The Barnhart Herbarium is under the supervision of the Preserve Ecologist and is primarily staffed by volunteers and community scientists, who are involved in the collection of plant specimens and the curation and maintenance of the Herbarium.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="f25eba75-3d89-4937-9a1f-d9562dbfe673" id="80"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=80</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>UNLV</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>UNLV - College of Southern Nevada; Wesley E. Niles Herbarium</collectionName><onlineUrl>https://www.csn.edu/schools/school-of-science-engineering-and-mathematics/department-of-biological-sciences/herbarium</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>UNLV - College of Southern Nevada; Wesley E. Niles Herbarium (UNLV-UNLV)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Mahrt</surName><givenName>Matthew</givenName></individualName><positionName>Curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>matthew.mahrt@csn.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Hooker</surName><givenName>Marcus</givenName></individualName><positionName>Collection Manager</positionName><electronicMailAddress>marcus.hooker@csn.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1970 by Dr. Wesley E. Niles, the herbarium now holds about 70,000 specimens. Its primary focus is the vascular plant diversity in the Mojave Desert regions of Nevada, Utah, Arizona, and California. In 2023, the herbarium was transferred to the College of Southern Nevada.&amp;nbsp; It is housed in the building A of the Henderson campus. Important collections include those of T. Ackerman (Desert National Wildlife Refuge); J. C. Beatley (Nevada Test Site); V. Bostick (central and southern Nevada); D. Charlet (Nevada); I.W. Clokey (Spring Mountains); M.Kurzius, D. Schramm, P. Peterson, and C. Annabel (Death Valley, California, and Nevada); S. Meyer (southern Nevada); A. Tiehm, A. Pinzl, and H. Mozingo (central and northern Nevada); W. Niles, P. Leary, J. Holland, and J. Alexander (Nevada, California, and Arizona), and L. Stark (bryophytes of southwestern deserts).&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email marcus.hooker@csn.edu to request access to redacted data.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="216e027d-46e2-494d-99e9-02a7aedc13c1" id="81"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=81</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>OSC</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>OSC - Oregon State University Vascular Plant Collection</collectionName><onlineUrl>https://bpp.oregonstate.edu/herbarium</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>Oregon State University</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>James Mickley</surName><givenName></givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>james.mickley@oregonstate.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;The Oregon State University Herbarium (OSC) houses approximately 550,000 vascular plant, bryophyte, algal, and fungal specimens. The collections are worldwide in scope, with a focus on the state of Oregon and the Pacific Northwest of the United States and Canada. Our vascular plant collection also includes the ORE and WILLU herbaria, and specimens should be cited based on the original herbarium. Square brackets indicate interpreted information not on the original label.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&lt;pre style="box-sizing: border-box; overflow: auto; font-size: 13px; color: #333333; font-family: Menlo, Monaco, Consolas, 'Courier New', monospace; padding: 9px; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 9.5px; line-height: 1.42857; word-break: break-all; overflow-wrap: break-word; background-color: #f5f5f5; border: 1px solid #cccccc; border-radius: 2px;"&gt;&lt;code style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: inherit; padding: 0px; font-family: Menlo, Monaco, Consolas, 'Courier New', monospace; color: inherit; background-color: transparent; border-radius: 0px; white-space: pre-wrap;"&gt;&lt;iframe style="width: 140px; height: 24px;" src="https://www.gbif.org/api/widgets/literature/button?gbifDatasetKey=b9f2645b-a5e0-4f24-aa97-eef1f6968fe8" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/code&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: Source Sans Pro,sans-serif !important; font-size: 1rem; vertical-align: top;"&gt; Previous dataset version: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;code style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: inherit; padding: 0px; font-family: Menlo, Monaco, Consolas, 'Courier New', monospace; color: inherit; background-color: transparent; border-radius: 0px; white-space: pre-wrap;"&gt;&lt;iframe style="width: 140px; height: 24px;" src="https://www.gbif.org/api/widgets/literature/button?gbifDatasetKey=84aa5ee4-f762-11e1-a439-00145eb45e9a" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="3d9e914e-d5a2-4aed-9b67-6913841a7cff" id="82"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=82</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>SOC</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>SOC - Southern Oregon University Herbarium</collectionName><onlineUrl>https://sou.edu/academics/biology/facilities/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>SOC - Southern Oregon University Herbarium (SOC-SOC)</additionalInfo><abstract></abstract><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Steven Jessup, Director</surName></individualName></associatedParty></collection><collection identifier="a3c24120-c916-42d1-ac52-d8d9e2992592" id="87"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=87</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>STNF</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>STNF - Shasta-Trinity National Forest Herbarium</collectionName><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>STNF - Shasta-Trinity National Forest Herbarium (STNF-STNF)</additionalInfo><abstract></abstract><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Strawsine</surName><givenName>Merissa</givenName></individualName><positionName>Forest Botanist</positionName><electronicMailAddress>merissa.strawsine@usda.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Kierstead</surName><givenName>Julie</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>Julie.Kierstead@usda.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty></collection><collection identifier="99daef92-479a-4555-91be-73987df3bc50" id="89"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=89</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>RENO</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>V</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>RENO - University of Nevada, Reno Herbarium</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://swbiodiversity.org/seinet/content/collicon/reno.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>RENO - University of Nevada, Reno Herbarium (RENO-RENO)</additionalInfo><abstract></abstract><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Tiehm</surName><givenName>Arnold</givenName></individualName><positionName>Curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>atiehm@att.net</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty></collection><collection identifier="b5fc33af-088c-4411-98a3-980134419103" id="91"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=91</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>US</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>US - Smithsonian Institution, National Museum of Natural History</collectionName><onlineUrl>http://collections.nmnh.si.edu/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>US - Smithsonian Institution, National Museum of Natural History (US-US)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>manager</surName><givenName>Collection</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>USNH@si.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #4e565f; font-family: Roboto, 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; background-color: #ffffff;"&gt;Public records of accessioned specimens curated by the National Museum of Natural History, Smithsonian Institution. These data are from the Department of Botany.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="91683e51-9c8f-4b13-8990-1b3814a94734" id="95"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=95</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>Harvard</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>Harvard University Herbaria: Vascular Plants (California, Oregon, Nevada, Baja California)</collectionName><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>Harvard University Herbaria: Vascular Plants (California, Oregon, Nevada, Baja California) (Harvard-Harvard)</additionalInfo><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #4e565f; font-family: Roboto, 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 16px; background-color: #ffffff;"&gt;This dataset contains all digitized vascular plant specimen records stewarded by the Harvard University Herbaria and collected in California, Oregon, Nevada, or Baja California. The Harvard University Herbaria, with over 5 million specimens, is the world&amp;rsquo;s largest University Herbaria. Included in the Herbaria are what were once six separate herbarium collections: * Herbarium of the Arnold Arboretum (A) * Economic Herbarium of Oakes Ames (ECON) * Oakes Ames Orchid Herbarium (AMES) * Farlow Herbarium (FH) * Gray Herbarium (GH) * New England Botanical Club Herbarium (NEBC). DarwinCore data follows the &lt;a href="https://code.google.com/archive/p/applecore/"&gt;AppleCore&lt;/a&gt; guidance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="67a7c27f-5689-40e0-a22e-4d8232264ddb" id="103"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=103</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>WHIS</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>WHIS - Whiskeytown National Recreation Area Herbarium</collectionName><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>WHIS - Whiskeytown National Recreation Area Herbarium (WHIS-WHIS)</additionalInfo><abstract></abstract><associatedParty><individualName><surName>McCarron</surName><givenName>Chris</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>c.mccarron@berkeley.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty></collection><collection identifier="6e4b99bf-d63a-4aa6-86a6-02b59a389cee" id="104"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=104</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>PINN</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>PINN - Pinnacles National Park</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/pinn.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://www.nps.gov/pinn/index.htm</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>PINN - Pinnacles National Park (PINN-PINN)</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Bones</surName><givenName>Virginia</givenName></individualName><positionName>Curator of Record</positionName><electronicMailAddress>Virgnia_Bones@nps.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Ryan</surName><givenName>Amelia</givenName></individualName><positionName>Vegetation Ecologist</positionName><electronicMailAddress>Amelia_Ryan@nps.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1936, the Pinnacles National Park herbarium contains pressed specimens of plants and fungi collected in Pinnacles National Park, California. All collecting at PINN requires an approved permit which can be accessed through &lt;a href="https://irma.nps.gov/RPRS/"&gt;https://irma.nps.gov/RPRS/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="2169410d-b8d7-4349-ae6e-b6313b60206b" id="108"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=108</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>MBNHM</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>MBNHM - Morro Bay Natural History Museum</collectionName><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>MBNHM - Morro Bay Natural History Museum (MBNHM-MBNHM)</additionalInfo><abstract></abstract><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Chase </surName><givenName>Robyn</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>robyn.chase@parks.ca.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Scheding</surName><givenName>Libbie</givenName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>Libbie.Scheding@parks.ca.gov</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty></collection><collection identifier="9a07fb3b-1ce5-4b0d-ae01-d809e5bfaf7b" id="110"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=110</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>BMR</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>BMR - The Peter G. Connors Herbarium at Bodega Marine Reserve</collectionName><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>Regents of the University of California</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Olyarnik</surName><givenName>Suzanne</givenName></individualName><positionName>Director</positionName><electronicMailAddress>svolyarnik@ucdavis.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Sones</surName><givenName>Jackie</givenName></individualName><positionName>Research Coordinator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>jlsones@ucdavis.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10pt; font-family: Arial;" data-sheets-value="{&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;:2,&amp;quot;2&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Pteridophytes, angiosperms&amp;quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&amp;quot;2&amp;quot;:513,&amp;quot;3&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;:0},&amp;quot;12&amp;quot;:0}"&gt;Pteridophytes, angiosperms&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="96925d6e-0c52-4d39-858d-b6426332a075" id="119"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=119</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>SCNHM</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>SCNHM - Sierra College Natural History Museum</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://cch2.org/portal/content/collicon/scnhm.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://www.sierracollege.edu/campus-life/things-to-do-on-campus/natural-history-museum/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>Sierra College Natural History Museum</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Matzer</surName><givenName>Laura</givenName></individualName><positionName>Director</positionName><electronicMailAddress>lmatzer@sierracollege.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Bromm</surName><givenName>George</givenName></individualName><positionName>Collection Manager</positionName><electronicMailAddress>gbromm@sierracollege.edu</electronicMailAddress></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;SCNHM comprises approximately 20,000 specimens representing an extensive range of natural history epochs.&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="6516ebe0-f4fb-4a34-8727-956f492a9d62" id="124"><alternateIdentifier>https://cch2.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=124</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>UCSD</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>UCSD - University of California San Diego Vascular Plants</collectionName><onlineUrl>https://nrs.ucsd.edu/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>Regents of the University of California</additionalInfo><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Uyeda</surName><givenName>Kellie</givenName></individualName><positionName>Co-curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>kuyeda@ucsd.edu</electronicMailAddress><userId>https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7043-3870</userId></associatedParty><associatedParty><individualName><surName>Rodriguez</surName><givenName>Clarissa</givenName></individualName><positionName>Co-curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>clr005@ucsd.edu</electronicMailAddress><userId>https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6898-8113</userId></associatedParty><abstract><para>&lt;p&gt;Vascular plants within the four UC San Diego Natural Reserves&lt;/p&gt;</para></abstract></collection></symbiota></metadata></additionalMetadata></eml:eml>
